yo yo good morning
good morning periscope hello periscope
good morning
wait for a few people to get in here
I'll show you what we're working with
today um so you're welcome my name is
George if this is your first time
joining us we are common AI and like I
said two years ago we're gonna win
self-driving cars so let's flip you guys
around here thank you thank you it is it
is a lovely hoodie it's it's similarly
priced to Kanye West's t-shirt all night
I know I slept a little bit I was on I I
conferenced into Paris autonomy this
morning I was actually supposed to be in
France right now but due to some
manufacturing issues with our products I
stayed here but they've all been sorted
out we are good to go and that's why we
went ahead with the launch today so
let's flip you guys around and let's
take a look
so on the left here this is the common
AI shop down on the right here is the
new common a I website and that's our
slogan ghost riding for the masses do we
have it patented
we don't have Pat xergiok we ship
products they're high quality well we
try our best to make them high quality
like our website all right thank you
thank you you know patents I I saw like
a infographic comparing like the
autonomous race to who has the most
patents who cares who is the best
self-driving car right now if you want
to buy one I'd say it's Tesla if you
want to steal one into its way no don't
steal away no card and encourage you to
steal away no car but you another coding
Paris ago maybe ghost riding for the
masses joining our expensive network of
drivers and improve your car experience
today so this is our product lineup this
here is the e on dash cam dev kit yeah
it's pretty nice that's kind of what it
looks like from the back this is ring
shiver Plus which is an upgraded version
of our dash cam software which runs on
iOS and Android you can get them right
now thank you I'm - conduct get chronic
page it will run Spotify ways and chip
applause
giving you basically everything you need
on a dashboard what's the major
difference with neo few things we
integrated the fan solution built in it
just has one mini USB port this is a
much better cooling solution it can
charge much faster it can draw much
higher power yeah and it looks a lot
better it doesn't replace your rear-view
mirror anymore you know we're a big fan
of keeping regulators happy so is there
a rearview mirror mount attachment I
mean right now what we ship is a GoPro
mount attached
which you can put on your on your
windshield assuming that's legal in your
state you'll also be able to switch it
so it's actually symmetrical from the
top and bottom but you'll be able to
switch it and put that mount on the
bottom and actually stick it on your
dashboard as well so you'll be able to
go over ways with it as far as rearview
mirrors go like if you build one that's
that's that's you but no we won't be
shipping without everything their
replacement so yeah this is the shop we
have you know dash cam dev kit we also
have the Panda obd2 dongle um
unlike a lot of hardware startups you
know a lot of hardware startups are like
okay we're gonna price the thing as high
as we can and then we're gonna lower the
price over time we're gonna price it as
low as we can and we're gonna raise the
price over time we want to reward early
adopters so pandas have gone up a little
there now $99 but there's still a great
deal you know a lot of the software that
was just promised when we first launched
the Panda like elm327 and J 2534 are now
live or almost close to live the
software is a lot more stable so far is
open sourced by the way this is the
panel firmware got a few giraffes I'll
go get the to the 128 gigs I'll figure
out a fair way to do it here's our
giraffe line out on the left that's a
Toyota giraffe on the right it's a Honda
giraffe Mohandas giraffes are going into
production you can see that they're
nicely filled a little bit with epoxy
yeah I know I know hundred of these
cases downstairs they look pretty good
to try to ship that soon the Toyota
giraffes take a little bit longer which
shouldn't be too long you see the purple
board is in there so it's still a nosh
park board purple eyes for the prototype
but we have these Boyd's we have any 200
these Boyd's on order in green so
they'll be plenty of giraffes to go
around we can spin up production
so fast we have an army of 3d printers
now I've been showing that off on
Twitter I love our army there's another
Rhian over there and here's a little
pyramid the pyramid had kind of seen
better days here's a here's a neon
without out with that amount it's really
easy to just undo those four screws and
pull that out they're interchangeable
different different mounting angles are
supported so depending on like how steep
your windshield is we're going to
include what I believe - the one on and
then the replacement one you'll just be
able to take that off with a uh with a
hex screwdriver
figure it out we'll see everybody we
have videos actually these are all these
are all one plug boxes here I'm so we do
have we do have quite a few one pluses
there's a lot more in the basement so
you know
now we've shipped out 1300 pandas and
1300 if something is a lot of something
not as many as grains of rice and as a
Mitch Hedberg Joe but it's like rice is
really good when you want to see here's
that
down here we were just using this
possess the Aeons um so yeah if I plug
in I plug in this USB cable here so I
that USB cable connects over here
to the Panda
I'm we're gonna include a short USB
cable on a long USB cable there's a
Honda giraffe there's play think Honda
simulator right there so I can just like
turn this on it will go to dash cam mode
I'm gonna put this UI a little bit
type-c know it's me be um the original
prototypes head of it had a C connector
here but uh we switched it to mini B
because it's a really a more reliable
connector like you know you want you
want to be able to like put a bit of
force on me as well make sure it's not
gonna break we had we had some issues
with the secant if there's also much
self driving so no so the UM we don't
ship any self driving Harbor due to
regulatory reasons we ship we just ship
open pilot and you can install open
pilot on your on your support hardware
but no this is visited dash cam that run
ship the plus working our way up working
our way back to selling a self driving
kit but the regulator's approval we love
regulators before making regulators
happy
yeah there's a bunch of us what's the
benefit of chevre Plaza worship a few
things I mean the easiest one the most
practical benefit is the fact that you
don't have to like hug the phone on your
dashboard this just stays up there Auto
Start Auto stop
you also get much higher quality the the
camera runs I believe right now it's 20
FPS but I believe we're gonna get that
up to 60 super high quality videos that
you know well beyond what you can get
from a phone because we can we have a
lot of we have a lot of thermal budget
and a lot of power budget we don't know
interruptions are going to happen this
is another thing you're not gonna get
any interruptions also you get much
improved localization so if you upload
to the comic cloud and all these things
are in the shared comic cloud so you'll
be able to log in with new shipper
account on iOS
all your shifter plus routes your open
pilot routes your iOS routes our and
routes like they all came from the same
place but you get a much improved
localization so if you look on Scheffer
and you see like when you drive around a
city you know you get like the phone gps
like this i'm with this mounted in a car
we can run much better location recovery
stuff
the other big thing about shiver plus is
hopefully at launch even we're gonna
roll out forward collision warning in
here so if you're about to crash into
something in front of you this will give
you an alert we can start looking into
lane departure warning path departure
warning and these will all be software
upgrades that'll just come out on your
device you didn't have to think about it
OTA is Kiyo's making fun of GM this
morning for not having OTA then someone
was claiming GM does i don't know i
haven't seen it I know tested us Tesla
the iOS we want to be the Android when
to the sweet hoodie ship is for day
because I think we can get the hoodies
fashion that I'm they really are super
nice hoodies the cava is embroidered
like important it's like a sewing
machine we really want to just get the
nicest hoodie and price it at an absurd
price but they are nice they come in the
medium/large size medium/large so let's
see what else do you guys want to see
I can show off the new ship perhaps you
need a dedicated sim that's up to you um
we're gonna make it work over with the
sim or with Wi-Fi and you'll be able to
sync it just like the shipper app it's
gonna have the same toggle that you have
in the chauffeur app that same upload
over cellular toggle any thoughts on
dual camera phone deployments they're
not that useful
now the bokeh effect is only useful at
really short distances so yeah these are
our our development phones here
I got a high phone a and galaxy s Sh so
you guys have all seen this is just
Scheffer will it run open pilot No so
the eon runs schiffer plus at least when
we when we ship it though they are you
know very hackable so if you decide to
run something else on it that's up to
you
we don't ship any stuff running up about
open palette is open-source software
forward collision warning eventually
coming to regular shipper eventually
eventually so it'll come to shiver plus
long before it'll come to shiver show
the battalion of Zorro axis yeah we can
we can take walk let's take a little
walk you want to go I want to go I want
to go visit our printers go visit our
printers remote start from phone that's
pretty cool websites new products next
step well ship these products and
deliver a great experience you can check
out our pack
pretty cool
here's our army apprentice they're not
Frankie's early it's very early here
these critters are broken the place we
bought becoming something you got to fix
them tonight
thoughts on GM's effort let me tell you
it was level 5 at Hertz I believe Google
and Tesla may even cruise Navy crews may
be cursed I wouldn't say GM kind of boat
you know as much as I make fun of the
guy
pruners look at the printer as I love
printers here's our data center all the
data center got moved around a little
bit
what's the price
yawns are 699 and hoodies are 129 oh man
look at all those cooler went bad Oh oh
poor GPU sleep one but we have GPU
slaves five of six now we're expanding
our GPU army oh good it looks like we're
training something that's good thank you
see what we got back here testing out
this panda that's pretty nice it's
pretty nice
Honda giraffe case is all here Honda
giraffes are ready to go yeah cooling is
much better than the
sup guys I'm excited I'm gonna go for
some breakfast I'm really excited about
breakfast when was the race and he's
doing pretty well he's doing great
uh uh we're super happy with the new
Schafer app we also hired designer
Andrew so that whole team is a handy and
Andrew phenomenal work you know really
great job on though on the website in
the shop good morning that's my desk
because my desk is my passion and I
should have anything up on the screen my
desk
I'm cranky right it's alright I'll give
him a bonus today he's actually Hawaii
he's my wife what he gets back with
Philip said comma dot ai if you want to
go to the shop it's just shop calm about
AI their slack here's an empty screen no
I can't have a guy us 11 so will feed on
partnering or even really competing as
much as we trash talk we're big on
building so we're gonna build the
hardware that you need to make your
Honda's in Toyotas great volt board
compatible I don't I don't have a whole
board know much about the Volt
but maybe uh yeah if the vault board has
USB yeah should work what do i pitch to
investors what do I need investors for
buy my products let's get rich let's be
profitable
we love you LAN now have you guys
look at that
shiver pluses running on your phone let
me know if you like it um yeah the the
VAR b ard is cool guessing this poster
this is why we don't build cars all that
pitch to the investors well it went well
and then I was like me we don't get more
money maybe we should just sell our
products and see how they sell
yeah our products sell well we won't
need more money if our products sell
okay we'll get more money we might get
more money anyway we'll see we'll see
the money is definitely on the table
when we want it you know just compare us
to the other startups you started in a
similar time to us in this space I think
we're killing it it's computer broke
this computer
we put it in the car and the inverter
kind of went crazy and it broke the
motherboard on the poor computer
any other questions guys open pilots
security features I was talking about
common security yeah so again these
things will all roll out and shiver Plus
first I would love to see shiver Plus
start to become a security system for
your car right if you leave that in
there you'll be able to you know none of
this is launched yet this is planned
you'll be able to basically it'll
function as a car alarm right if
somebody disturbs your car while it's
parked and you're running shiver plus
it'll send that video up to the cloud
you'll have like a security route do
push notifications to your phone you
know all that good stuff what we want to
do is build what the car manufacturers
never could as aftermarket stuff and
that's really what what ian is um
shipper plus we'll work with neo or only
panda no promises on Neo support for
shipper plus it may work it may not
we're not gonna go out of our way to
break it but we're not gonna go out of
our way to support it either ship
applause is really designed for aeons a
lot of because it uses all I use a lot
of power that way isn't spotify uses a
lot of power does it record both cameras
um so we're gonna add an option for the
front camera definitely opt in not opt
out for like uber drivers and people who
want that it's it's certainly on the
list and we're gonna get a lot more
serious about these kind of features
now that we've were shipping eons we're
shipping ship for plus ya audio will be
an option as well again I'm gonna throw
you're gonna throw a warning up on the
audio option front camera the audio
option you know you don't want you don't
want to activate that unless you know
exactly what you're doing you know just
just recording audio and your sound
recording audio on your car what
toolchain did we use i didn't do it
one of the people who work here did I'd
have to ask him I think we just use
whatever check out the Android thing you
like use that repo command you build you
wait six hours and you're gonna Android
Rob haha but yeah we'll be shipping
we'll be shipping out a new version in
the US as well should work we should try
to keep the back work battle of Neos
but definitely for aeons what up with
common points comments are great we love
common points guys check out the quality
so I've seen the quality side
lane-change support for open pilot you
know what you know what I always say Oh
a lane change means a sensor there who's
in the office right now me uh what's fsd
full self-driving yeah yeah we see it
commoditize cuz we're gonna do it
and uh
hippo I got become a hippo not for sale
maybe few I don't other people in Tamil
if you yeah but it's 6:00 in the morning
and they're home sleeping cool huh
you could maybe go find the Cole the
Koala was like it was a bad idea they
would call it was a bad I wanted uncle
Wallace
Eddie of the madam I told you guys about
koalas
is my here's my collection of books can
we make a profit yeah
we can make a profit Oh will you make a
profit it's not huge but hopefully
enough to stay in business
um what will be our advantage the fact
that we're going to actually work in
cars that already exist we're the only
one I know is like we're not gonna build
cars we're gonna build user installable
after
and that's that's the key so the user
can buy it we want to put this stuff on
Amazon Prime man and I was on prime
yourself a self-driving car someday
someday for now it's only a dashcam we
do still have a cook
we like cook to cook his grades great
guy making great food I love food cooks
hell I'm eating would be on work with so
would be on work I mean yet yield and
chef or plus will work on any car as a
dashcam um if you want to use the like
the functionality that taps into the car
that's that's that's hit or miss
depending on the car but ya know as far
as a dash cam ways and Spotify don't
work on anything you put it on a bike if
you want to maybe even try to no pedal
pedal in your little track down the
street and got your yeon mount at their
Haven Scheffer learns from everything
cool thanks for joining
um we've got some press coming out later
today so let's hope today goes well
thanks guys
oh I'm still here would training take
longer if you went 60fps no wood
attachment of an external stereo camera
work that's hard to do because bandwidth
from the USB camera is a very very high
bandwidth and thank you wait how do I
swiped it Oh
iOS 11 thing okay I figured out I found
the X now it's really by